The President:
Speaker 1: Thank you. Thank you. Thank you very much. And thank you for
Speaker 2: going out to see where this is. Jamie Hathaway told me you were going there and sent me a couple of pictures when you were there. And when you see it, you fully understand it. Tim Reeser, who is here, has worked for decades on this issue,
Speaker 2: knows what it's like to actually go to the landmine fields. My wife and I have
gone to
Speaker 2: them many times. She's a registered nurse and she understands what it is. Tim and I and some others will be in Vietnam week after next. And we use the Leahy War Victims Fund
Speaker 2: years ago when President George H.W. Bush wanted to do something to show that we were reaching out to Vietnam. And we did this, and you've had similar experiences, Rich, I'm sure, with Meg. We went on a very, very hot day. Southern part of Vietnam, we're going to where they're setting up
the Lady of
Speaker 2: War Victims Fund for Prosthetics for people who
had
Speaker 2: been crawling since the war. There was a man, a very small man, no legs, sitting there. They're introducing me in Vietnamese, and periodically say my name, and he's just staring at me. And I think he must see a large American, and must hate me. And I'll never forget, I was in an open neck shirt, and chinos, and they
said,
When
Speaker 2: they finished was you go pick him up and put him in the wheelchair all the time He stared at me. I picked him up
Speaker 3: carefully put him in the wheelchair Started
to get
Speaker 3: back up. He grabbed my shirt. He pulled me down. He kissed me now You have stories like that, but I've also you think what mag does you don't know how terrifying it is to be in one of these landmine fields like they
are and
I'm
Speaker 3: glad we were able to show some of these pictures because there are rarely ever happy endings in these stories. When you go out, I mean, I remember being, staying here and I started to move and the guy grabbed me back. He said, "Don't go another inch," and detected there was a land mine there. I was in one war zone visiting a young teenage girl in the hospital, lost both legs.
Her
Speaker 3: story was that the war started, her parents sent her away, where she'd be safe. Hostility stopped. She's coming back, she spots her parents, she's running down the road, speaking to them in their language, calling out to both of them, landmine goes off, she lost both legs. I mean, there are no happy endings. We've had Bill Clinton worked at, saying we should start finding alternatives to
Speaker 4: landmines.
Speaker 4: Under the Leahy Law, we can't export landmines from this country, and incidentally, the one time all 100 senators came together on something,
but we
Speaker 2: didn't sign the landmine treaty. We didn't sign it in two terms of President Bush, even though I urged him to. President Obama, I think he gets tired of the number of times I talk to him about
it.
The
Speaker 2: United States of America, the most
Speaker 1: powerful nation on earth, should sign the landmine treaty. We should sign it today and set that example. Again, the
Speaker 3: thing to remember, there are no happy
endings
Speaker 2: when you're facing a landmine. Thank goodness for MAG, those who help pull up these landmines. They're very easy to put
down.
You
Speaker 2: can put down, Jamie, as you know, you can put down hundreds, you can fill this room in a matter of seconds. But
it might
Speaker 2: take you weeks to pull them back up.
If our
Speaker 4: children, if my grandchildren lived in
an area
Speaker 4: where we had to worry about landmines, wouldn't everybody in this country come together and say, sign the treaty, stop the landmines, make it criminal to use them? That's what we have to do. So keep fighting, and I just got the word, I got three minutes left in a roll call vote. I'd rather stay here with you. But thank you all very, very much.